Sercan Türkmen

Gender: Male, Marital Status: Single Nationality: Turkey, Born: 4 March 1993 Address: Kaijonharju 90570, Oulu, Finland

Tel. +358 44 951 8989

■ & S sercanturkmen@outlook.com

■ **Comparison**

■ **Compariso

🔾 sercant in sercanturkmen 🖹 sercanturkmen

SUMMARY

I believe the code is not just something that works, it should be readable, maintainable and testable. Because it has its own life cycle and machine will understand everything if it's in the correct syntax but the developers will be reading the code many times. I am experienced with most of the software development tools and methodologies including Scrum, Git, TDD, continuous integration for mobile platforms. Furthermore, thanks to my graduate degree, I have gained new viewpoints in software engineering and its direction. I aim to combine my research experience with my sectoral background for novel approaches to help build better experiences for everyone.

EDUCATION

University of Oulu, Oulu, FIN

M.Sc., Artificial Intelligence, September 2017 (ongoing)

• Current GPA: 4.60/5.0

• Thesis: Inpainting Objects in Augmented Reality (proposed title)

• Supervisor: Janne Heikkilä, Prof.

Izmir Institute of Technology, Izmir, TUR

B.Sc., Computer Engineering (taught in English), January 2016

• GPA: 3.30/4.0

• Thesis: Application of Artificial Intelligence on a Platformer Type Game Based on User Experience

• Supervisor: Selma Tekir, Asst. Prof.

Jönköping University, Jönköping, SWE

Exchange Student, Fall 2014

• Studied courses: Agile Project, Android Development.

WORK Experience

Research Assistant, University of Oulu

February 2018 - Present

Open-source Android library development on various mobile sensors using Kotlin. Real-time semantic segmentation with CNN, object tracking, and augmented reality on mobile devices.

Intern Developer, ROHM Semiconductor Oulu

April 2018 - August 2018

Windows application development using XAML with C# as a part-time developer.

Software Developer, Digitov Games

January 2015 - September 2017

Have worked both front-end and the game engine side of the projects using Haxe. For the native platform adaptation, have used Java, Javascript, C++, and Objective-c. Played a major role as a release engineer. With a small compact team we released four game titles with over 1 million downloads in total on mobile platforms.

Intern, Reo-Tek

Summer 2013

Summer internship about scripting in Unity3D.

Professional Work

AWARE Framework, University of Oulu

February 2018 - September 2018

AWARE is an Android framework dedicated to instrument, infer, log and share mobile context information, for application developers, researchers and smartphone users. I have re-designed the framework to allow modular implementation of new sensors. Also, using this core design, I have re-implemented many Android sensors in Kotlin language and used Room as a local database.

Digi Okey, Digitov Games

Late 2016

A template version of our other title 'Okey Extra'. Using this template we made three other titles to replace two out-dated games Rakkip Okey and Tekel Okey, and a new one called Can Okey.

Yuzbir Extra, Digitoy Games

Early 2016

A social casino board game developed using Haxe, and available on Facebook, App Store, and Play Store. 101 Okey is a popular Turkish board game based on Rummy. During the development, I was the lead front-end developer in charge of code design and implementation.

Poker Extra, Digitoy Games

Late 2015

A Texas Hold'em poker game. I had the role of the single front-end developer during the development and I was in charge of all aspects of the code. Poker Extra is currently available on Facebook, App Store, and Play Store. I was in charge of maintaining the game regularly and keeping the code up-to-date.

Okey Extra, Digitoy Games

Early 2015

A social casino turkish board game similar to Rummy. I was one of the front-end developers in the project programming using haxe. After the release of the game and to the end of my employment, I was maintaining bug fixes and visual design updates.

INDEPENDENT Work Dawn

The implementation of my thesis work, a platformer game based on the user context. It adjusts the difficulty of the environment, AI, and add or delete some game mechanics during the gameplay without any predefined setting in the traditional sense (ex. easy, medium, hard).

Paper Plane Challenge

2014

2015

An 8-bit arcade game and written with C++ using Cocos2d-x and Box2D. (Unlisted from Google Play store.)

The Longing 2014

A 2D platformer-puzzle-skill game written in Java using LibGDX and Box2D in 48 hours starting from scratch. This game is developed for a Game Jam event called BuildUp 2014.

Bomberman Clone 2014

A clone of the Bomberman as a course project. Game is written using Java language and Slick2D library.

Portal Prisoner 2013

An 8-bit puzzle-adventure game inspired by Valve's 'Portal' and written using C++ language, Cocos2d-x and Box2D libraries. (Unlisted from Google Play store.)

Publications

Türkmen, S., & Heikkilä, J. (2019). An efficient solution for semantic segmentation: ShuffleNet V2 with atrous separable convolutions. arXiv preprint arXiv:1902.07476.

SCHOLARSHIPS

City of Oulu Living Cost Scholarship, 4 000€

CI

January 2019

Academic success; credit accumulation and grade point average. Applicant must have achieved at least 55 ECTS during their 1st academic year (their 1st year of the Master studies) at the University of Oulu.

International Master's Scholarship, 10 000€ + 10 000€

September 2017

University of Oulu for studies in the Master's Programme in Computer Science and Engineering.

LANGUAGES

Turkish (mother tongue), English (advanced level¹), Japanese (entry level), Finnish (entry level)

SKILLS

Programming Languages

	Familiar	— Confident —	- Proficient
Kotlin, Haxe, Python			_
Java, SQL			_
C, C++			
C#	$\overline{}$		
Bash	_		
		Technologies	
	Familiar	— Confident —	- Proficient
OOP, TDD, Git			_
Semantic Segmentation			
Tensorflow, Jira, Android			

 $^{^{1}2015}$ IELTS 7.0/9.0